Kenechukwu Ajufo

Frontend Web Engineer

kenechukwu.ajufo@gmail.com | + 353 85 784 6705 | /in/kene-ajufo | Github | Blog | https://kxnxchukwu.github.io

Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, SCSS, Python, C # **Libraries & Frameworks**: React, Redux, Sagas, Express, Bootstrap, jQuery, ASP.Net MVC, Mongoose, EJS, styled-components, GatsbyJS, JEST (Familiar using these libraries and frameworks to build and test web applications)

Software/IDEs/Tools: Git & GitHub (Familiar using Git & GitHub for version control), NPM, Chrome Developer Tools, React Developer Tools, Visual Studio Code, Webpack. (Used daily). Postman, Heroku, Netlify (Used tools to deploy web applications)

Data Management: Microsoft SQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL. (Familiar with querying, storing using these Database Management Tools)

Operating Systems: Windows (Intermediate), Linux (Elementary), MacOS (Elementary)

Methodologies: Agile, SCRUM, Test-Driven Development

Profile

Frontend Web Engineer interested in solving real world problems using cutting edge technology. 2 plus years professional experience working with multiple web programming languages and technologies. I have a strong understanding of the principles of Responsive Design, Grids, Layout, Typography, JavaScript and React. I love building things that live on the web.

Career History

bxp Software Dublin, Ireland

Jan. 2022 - Present

Frontend Engineer

- API Integration.
- Web App Development with PWA.
- Debugging, Troubleshooting and Bug Fixing.

National College of Ireland Dublin, Ireland

Sep. 2020 - Mar. 2022

Computing Lab Assistant

• Assist undergraduate, postgraduate and master's students with questions or queries they have during tutorials for the following modules - Database & Analytics Programming, Discrete Mathematics, Data Mining and

Machine Learning, Data Application Development/Programming for Big Data, Business Data Analysis, Distributed Systems, Operating Systems, Data Structures & Algorithms, Software Engineering, and Data and Web Mining.

- Solve technical issues like computer software installation for students.
- Manage breakout rooms during laboratory tutorials.
- Review and resolve bugs in student code written in Python, R & Java.

Key Achievement

Applied advanced knowledge obtained studying for an undergraduate and postgraduate degree to apply a
transferable skill set of critical analysis, academic research, diligence, organisational workflow optimisation,
knowledge articulation and proficiency in understanding fundamental technical texts and theories.

Chams Plc Lagos, Nigeria

Jan. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Software Developer

- Collaborated with a team of 3 developers to develop web applications for in-house and clients primarily using HTML, CSS, LESS, JavaScript, React, jQuery, SQL and ASP.NET Core MVC following best practices in Agile and QA.
- Worked in a team of three that upgraded existing web applications to ensure they met Accessibility requirements which boosted SEO by 10%.
- Designed and Developed interactive React Components using Styled-Components.
- Tracked and managed web applications with Version Control tool Git. Created new branches to test feature and merged them accordingly.
- Created unit tests with JEST.
- Worked closely with marketing, design, product, support, and software development to meet customers' needs.
- Adhered to the Software Development Lifecycle, observing the impact of existing features and anticipating future customer product need.

Key Achievement

• Navigated client interfacing issues that arose from most of the customer base lacking access to smartphones; architected a streamlined onboarding application portal that facilitated a convenient user experience.

Precise Financial Systems Lagos, Nigeria

Nov. 2017 - Oct. 2018

System Developer Intern

- Managed and routinely modified proprietary console application for automatically reading and importing Microsoft Excel and Text Files to SQL Server database using C# for Tier One Banks in Nigeria.
- Worked in a team that improved load time by 5%. The team and I also maintained codebase (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript) of proprietary web application for accounts reconciliation.
- Implemented LESS and split CSS stylesheets based on media queries decreasing page load time of propriety web application by 20%
- Participated in Daily Stand-Up Meetings, also investigated and resolved bugs in my code.

Key Achievement

• Functioned as a vital component in daily stand-up meetings to report the results of potential coding bugs investigations and resolutions.

Education

National College of Ireland Dublin, Ireland

Master of Science, Data Analytics, Second Class Upper Division

April 2021

Babcock University Ogun State, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

June 2017

Personal Projects

Crown Clothing App | GitHub Link

Simple eCommerce website built using Create React App.

Technologies Used: React, Redux, Sagas, Firebase, Sass, Redux Saga, Styled Components, Reselect, Stripe

Spotify Profile App | GitHub Link

A web app built with React that interacts with the Spotify API to visualize user's data.

Technologies Used: React, Express, Sass, Bootstrap, Styled Components

Countries App | GitHub Link

Countries App uses the Countries Rest API to show details of different countries in the world.

Technologies Used: React, React Animations, Bootstrap, Styled Components

Personal Interests

Personal Development: Listen to Front End Happy Hour Podcast to stay updated with advancements in Front End Web Development.